两分钟
Two minutes.
两分钟 讲一个主题
Two minutes, one topic that you have
向我解释一个概念
to explain to me what is it.
JavaScript Symbols
It is JavaScript Symbols.
开始
Go.
所以 JavaScript Symbols
So JavaScript Symbols.
有这个东西
They exist.
我知道
I'm aware.
这是一种新的原始类型
So this is a kind of a new primitive type.
是的
Yes, it is.
因为它们不是对象
Because they're not objects.
对吧
Right?
这是新的类型 如果你
And it's a new thing where if you
typeOf一个Symbol 显示的类型是Symbol
do type of one of these things it comes up with symbol
而不是对象 因为它是原始类型
rather than object because it's a primitive.
为什么？
Why?
我用它做什么？
What do I use them for?
它能做的事...
Well, so it's a way to-- because you
可以将它们用作对象的属性
can use them as object keys.
你可以创建一个symbol 而所做的只是-
So you can create a symbol and all you do is just--
不是object.myProperty
So instead of going, object dot my property,
而是object[symbol]
I go object--
把symbol放在方括号里
Open brackets, you can put a symbol in there,
你可以为symbol类型的属性赋值
and you can assign stuff to it.
symbol类型的属性是隐藏的
And it's kind of hidden.
是隐藏的但隐藏的不深
It's not super hidden, but it's kind of hidden.
symbol属性不可枚举
It's not innumerable.
哦 symbol属性不可枚举
Oh, it's not innumerable.
是的
Exactly.
所以 如果我用Object.keys()
So if I go like object dot keys
或类似函数 symbol属性将不会列出？
or whatever the function is, it won't be listed?
是的
Yep.
这意味着...我们有toJSON
And it means-- so we've got things like to JSON, right?
这是一种标准函数
And this is sort of a standard function where it will--
用它来将对象转换为JSON
that's how it will convert your object to JSON.
这很痛苦 因为toJSON
And it's a pain because it's that function
会和其他东西发生冲突
can clash with other stuff.
这有可能
It can happen.
所以想法是
So the idea is that there'll just
创建一个symbol，它是独一无二的
be this unique symbol created and that's
通过这种方式暴露类似toJSON这样的函数
where you would expose that sort of stuff
如果我们现在又做一次
if we did it again now.
哦 所以基本上我们用symbol
Oh, so basically we are using
以便把功能挂在平台上
that to allow you to hook it to things on the platform.
是的
Yes.
这就是迭代器的工作方式
And that's how iterators work.
对​​
Right.
我之前看到过
I actually saw that.
我从来不知道那是什么
I never knew what it was.
因此它可以创建你自己的对象甚至你自己的类
So it can make your own object or even your own class,
实现迭代器
I guess, iterable by using symbols.
通过symbols
By using symbols.
它们是平台上最独特的东西
And they're the most unique thing on the platform.
因为如果你两次调用Symbol
Because if you call symbol twice,
返回的symbol不一样
they're both unique across anything
即使你给他们起了相同的名字
even if you give them the same name.
所以对Symbol来说，你永远不会
So every symbol, you can never
重新创建相同的symbol 除非你
recreate the same symbol unless you
有确切的引用
have the exact reference to it.
除非你用符Symbol.for()
And except if you do symbol dot four,
然后传给它一个名字
and you give it a name.
这就是该名称对应的symbol
Then now that is a symbol for that name.
那是JavaScript中最不唯一的东西
And that is the least unique thing in JavaScript
在不同的iframe中也是相同的值
because that is the same value across I-frames as well.
这也是迭代器能跨iframe工作的原因
And that's how iterators work across I-frames too.
有趣
Interesting.
我不知道我是否为此写过博客
I wonder if I wrote a blog post about this.
这就是Symbols
And that's Symbols.
你不能随这首歌跳舞-
You can't dance along to this song as well as the--
我们需要更多的节奏
we need more rhythm.
我的意思是 我们可以跳机械舞
I mean, we can do the robot.
我觉得我们现在
I feel like we've
名字起的不太好
dropped the ball on trying to think
我们想不出能
of the names of things that are going
吸引人们眼球的名字
to draw people to these videos.
那么 这集为什么不叫“Symbol Whack”呢？
So why don't we just call it symbol whack.
JavaScript Symbol Whack.
JavaScript Symbol Whack
这就是这一集的内容
That's what that section was about.
我们会把它编辑到视频中
We'll edit that into the video.
好的
That's fine.